What's going on everyone? Welcome back to another
video. I'm James with the School of Hard Knocks.
We're out here in downtown Dallas, Texas, and this is
going to be a part two to our last video
of where we're asking millionaires in downtown
Dallas the best financial decision that they've
ever made. Stay tuned. A lot of amazing content
on the way. Let's go talk to some people.
What industry did you guys pursue a career in?
Well, I got my first degree in psychology, and
after I graduated, I realized I can't do much
with it. I went back and got my
master in management, and I got my information system
degree, but now I'm an owner of four companies.
As an entrepreneur, what is your best piece
of advice to someone wanting to start a business
in 2022?
I mean, hard work pays off. If you want to
be a business owner, you've got to put in the time.
A lot of people think, hey, I want to be
a business owner and work nine to five. It doesn't
work that way. What you put in
it is what you'll get out of it.
What has been the best financial decision that
you guys have ever made throughout your lifetime?
Pay off all my credit card. I never
wrecked up credit card debts again. Now I
charge and I pay it
by the end of the week.
Unless you can pay with cash, don't go buy anything.
Anything extravagant and go in debt.
What industry are you in?
Well, I'm in IT, technology.
And what advice would you
give someone pursuing the technology industry?
It's not easy. It's easier for
you now because everything's available online,
but at the time for me, it wasn't. Stick
with what you like to do, not necessarily what you
think you should do. You have to love
it so that you wake up in the morning,
doesn't feel like you're going to work.
From what you guys have seen throughout your
career, whether it's a certain skill set or
attribute for someone to possess when going out.
Social skills. Oh my goodness. I hire a
lot of people now. No social skills. Technology
is not a social skill.
What has been the best financial decision
that you've ever made throughout your lifetime?
Purchasing my house. Get your money back. Don't rent.
How much is it appreciated since you bought it?
About $200,000.
In what industry did you decide to pursue a career?
I'm a middle school counselor.
What's been the most rewarding thing about that?
I think seeing my students grow over the
years. Like saying like, you know, eighth grade
into like adults and being like, holy
shit, like you, it's different. Brand new.
What is your best piece of advice to
someone starting out in the real world today?
Don't make a mistake.
Don't take risks. I think we all so comfortable
and not taking a risk, but I think don't be
afraid to take a risk.
If you were to start from zero and you
had one year to make a million dollars and your
life depended on it, what would you do?
At that point I'd probably be bank robbing, you
know? I don't really know how to get a
million, you know? So not that great at it.
What is your best financial advice
to younger people in college right now?
Don't take loans and don't open credit
cards. Yeah. That's, that's about it. You know?
What industry did you pursue a
career in other than being Spider-Man?
Various odd jobs, you know,
construction, you know, firefighting, garbage disposal,
you know, usual.
What's the best financial decision
that you've made throughout your life?
Investing in myself. I've paid for so many
things that just wasn't it until I understood
that it's, it's going to be me. Pay for
me and then invest in yourself and get your equipment
and get your, your tools so that you can
be the best that you can be. Then you're going
to win. So my best
financial decision was investing in myself.
So do you think a college degree
is necessary for success in today's society?
You might not like this answer, but no, no,
I don't. You know, the things that they teach
you in college, just the whole school system, they
kind of like gear you to be a winner.
You're a worker bee. Everybody's got their place
in life. You know, you need the McDonald's
managers, you need the worker bees. But if
you're trying to make your own way and really
put a stamp on your life and like leave
a legacy for your family, you got to know what
it is that you want to do
and create some new shit for yourself.
If you were to go back to when you
were in high school or college, what's the best piece
of advice you'd tell your younger self?
Be intentional about what it is that
you want to accomplish. When you're intentional about
what it is you want to accomplish, you'll,
you're more likely to set up the correct steps
to make that come to fruition. If you're
not, if you're flippy floppy, you don't know
what it is that you want to do, then that's
kind of going to kind of be your path. A flippy
floppy, you don't know what to do path.
But if you're intentional, you're zeroed in, laser
focused on your goal, then
you're probably going to get there.
What has been the best financial decision
that you've ever made throughout your lifetime?
Marrying someone who has a good financial mind.
In my case, it was just finding a partner
who had similar aspirations and goals. And
we just spent a lifetime working towards those
aspirations and goals.
And what industry did you
decide to pursue a career in?
I was a public servant.
And throughout your career, what has been
the best financial decision that you've ever
made?
Invested in my family because my daughters
are the bombs. We raised them properly. They're
awesome, awesome young ladies, probably your age. And
my wife and I did the right thing.
We invested in our family.
Do you think a college degree is
necessary to be successful in today's society?
No. Why not?
Because you can have a trade, you can have
a work ethic. If you want to work and you
can outwork anybody.
Just a piece of paper that says you have
a college degree doesn't fit at my end of
the day. It means nothing.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Law enforcement.
What has been the best financial
decision that you've made throughout your lifetime?
The best one is once I moved down here.
Moving to Dallas?
Yeah, moving to Dallas and just taking
my money and not spending it on bull.
Where did you move from?
Mississippi.
Mississippi. And I guess why was Dallas a
good financial decision? Why was it a good
investment to move down here?
Because there ain't nothing in Mississippi at all.
I mean, I love home, but I feel like
if anybody wants to start a business, they
can start a business. And I think that's what's
going to be the best decision.
If you want to start something,
move. Move for your home town.
What would you say is the best
financial decision you've ever made in your lifetime?
Paying off all my debts. Debt's not always
a bad thing. You can always borrow money and
invest it, but staying low debt and high
income has always been the best because it allows
me to move whenever I want to move. Like
I'll sometimes fly to New York or I'll be here
in Dallas for the weekend. It's just always
having that income on the side to invest and
jump when the opportunity presents itself. So
basically just staying out of that hole
of debt.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Music.
Music for sure. Yeah. I would have beat subscription
sites. I still beat some rappers all the time.
We collab in the studio. We always bounce
ideas off of each other and motivate each
other. So that keeps me going every day for sure.
And what advice would you have for
someone looking to get into the music industry?
Practice. Yeah, practice for sure. And don't be
afraid of your creativity. A lot of people
think that they're not good enough or like
if they sing the song, they're going to get
a bad review. They're going to hurt their
ego. Don't worry about any of that because
the originality is what people look for nowadays basically.
If you were to go back to when you
were in either high school or college, what is the
best piece of advice you would tell your younger self?
I would tell myself to get more involved with
other people on campus. I mean you got to
learn to be an adult.
Thank you guys for tuning in to today's video.
We hope you guys enjoyed it. This wraps up
our trip to Dallas. We're headed back to Austin
right now. Got to talk to some really cool
people today, some business owners, find out
about their best financial decision and their
financial advice to you guys. So hope
you guys enjoyed. Stay tuned for more content
coming. Let's keep going.